For these reasons, we have selected
the five Eighty-Six, as well as the rest of Nordlicht,
for the mission to destroy the Morpho.
Detail Roster
This is my formal decision as
Western Theater commander.
September 2nd, Stellar Year 2149
Even you don't have the right
to overrule—
I know that.
I was ready for it.
But I want to know one thing.
General, this isn't a year-late attempt
at a "disinfection," is it?
There's no way that those children,
especially just the five of them,
can break through Legion-controlled territory.
Some of the officers had said
right when we took them in
that it was better to eliminate them
for the safety of the Federacy.
You were one of them.
I won't deny your wish
to protect what you care for.
However, this nation is built on justice.
It's not acceptable for a human to try to have his way
using violence, rather than using words.
So I'm asking you.
You can assure me this isn't
what it looks like, can't you?
Of course.
But...
I want to hear your thoughts.
On what?
They're not poor, pitiful children.
They're monsters, created by the
madness of the battlefield.
Are you willing to take them
into your beloved homeland?
Is that really what the Federacy should be?
Of course.
Those are my ideals
and the ideals of the nation I lead.
I speak on behalf
of the entire Federacy, after all.
I am responsible for executing
my duties with pride and dignity!
Understood.
Oh, no, it's pitch black.
You'll damage your eyes.
I'm not willing to listen
to alternative plans.
I know.
So I have a suggestion.
The reason you kept Nordlicht
split up into smaller platoons
was to keep the rest of the military
from realizing their strength, wasn't it, Richard?
The Republic weapons we captured—
Juggernauts, were they?
Once you've seen the combat logs on them,
it makes you want to do that.
A blade that cuts too well will either be avoided, or used until it breaks.
Either way, it won't end well.
In the end, your fears came true, though.
Don't get too attached.
Even if we ever-so-kindly took them in,
they would never forget the battlefield.
I don't know about that.
They're still kids in their mid-teens.
Right now, they're not used
to their new environment.
It's all they can do
to protect themselves.
But...
Someday they might get used
to this country
and long to have the things
that were stolen from them.
And even if they were still to choose
to live on the battlefield,
it should be their decision to make.
I'll wait until then.
However many years it takes.
Do you have a duty to go that far?
Of course.
It's our responsibility for arrogantly
trying to save our fellow humans
as you would a drowning puppy.
And you think a bloody blade,
forged and honed on the battlefield,
can understand human feelings?
We made the same bet before.
Do you remember?
I won then.
And the Legion took all your winnings.
Yes.
Grethe, you simply see
the dead in them. That's all.
You see what you can never get back.
So what if I do?
If you're that worried,
then that'll make this easier.
Those slow transport helicopters aren't appropriate
for my Reginleifs' big mission.
Give me permission to use it.
September 13th, Stellar Year 2149
"It," huh?
I never thought I'd see the day
the sealed door opened.
Sometimes living a long time
has its benefits.
"The sealed door"?
That's what some call it.
If it's sealed,
then it should be left that way.
Now, let's go.
What is this?
An old Imperial Air Force hangar.
For a prototype.
A prototype plane?
That's right.
It completed its test flights
and was about to enter mass production
when the war started, and the
base was temporarily abandoned.
This place is right next
to the border.
I guess the Legion took it over real quick, huh?
Why is it underground?
A bunch of reasons.
It's safer from bombing this way.
It also means the Legion didn't take it.
This is the X-C1 "Nachzehrer,"
a prototype ground-effect vehicle.
It's still sleeping right now, though.
It flies?
"Ground-effect vehicle"?
A plane that uses ground effect—
which occurs when you stay right
above the ground—to fly.
It can get you to the Morpho far faster
than a transport helicopter.
Um, I think I heard you say,
"right above the ground."
Yeah.
It flies only a few meters
above the ground!
It flies lower than a cruise missile,
making it hard for radar and AA missiles to locate!
That's the power of the Nachzehrer!
What an awful name.
A Nachzehrer is an old vampire legend
from the southeast part of the Federacy.
It rises from its grave
and wanders the graveyard
while dragging its shadow behind it,
and rings the church bell.
Yeah, that is a nasty name.
Wait! We'll run into buildings
if we're just a few meters off the ground.
This mission takes place
in former Imperial territory.
We have the geographic data.
The Legion doesn't make towns or homes.
We'll be fine.
What about the Legion themselves?
We avoid them, of course.
Lieutenant Nouzen can do that, right?
I can tell you where they are.
But will it really work?
This thing can't exactly turn on a dime,
so we'll have problems if we get ambushed.
But the three-country alliance will be handling
most of the enemies, so we don't need to worry.
And then what?
If we do get to the Morpho,
can we win?
And even if we do win,
we'll be in the middle of enemy territory.
How will we get back?
Well—
It's more important to take out the Morpho
than worry about how we'll get back.
But—
Are you going to ignore it?
You don't need me to tell you
what the result of that will be.
That said,
you seem to take it for granted
that this thing flies, but...
Who's going to pilot it?
Who else?
Me!
What do you think?
This isn't the time for jokes.
Who's really going to do it?
Me, as I said!
It's really me!
You're joking.
That's ridiculous!
It's really me!
October 7th, Stellar Year 2149
Come in.
Frederica.
I'm not leaving.
I came because I heard you were
throwing a tantrum about not leaving.
It's not a tantrum.
I'm a member of Nordlicht, too.
Why do I have to be
the only one to leave?
It wouldn't be allowed anyway.
You haven't forgotten what I said
about mascots being hostages, right?
An exception would be made
for the president's daughter.
But...
Why are you suddenly saying this?
You're the one who said that nobody else
has the right to decide how you live!
I also said it's best not to get involved
in someone's death if you don't have to.
And...
I remember its voice.
I don't need you to show me.
It should be the other way around!
I'm the one with the relationship to Kiriya!
You should be the ones to go home!
I'll talk to Grethe.
You managed to survive the awful battles
in the 86th district.
You can't die in a plan like this.
I'll handle this.
You can see your knight,
but not the other Legion.
If you head in,
you and everyone else will die.
But—!
Why are you so insistent on sending us
back to the rear?
Didn't you want us to kill your knight?
Or maybe you don't really
want them dead at all?
Then head home. And forget it.
You don't want to end up like me, right?
And what about you?
Whom do you think you're talking to?
You followed your own brother onto
the battlefield and slew his ghost.
Why are you telling me now that
I can't chase my own ghost?
Why are you telling me
I can't achieve my goal?
You realize on some level,
don't you?
That having no goal,
no place to call "home,"
clinging only to pride to keep you alive,
is what made that pathetic ghost what he is!
Do you want to end up the same way?
I'm not your knight.
You're free to see me in him if you like.
But I don't want to be forced
to join in your regret and atonement.
You don't understand!
I'm telling you not to go!
Why don't you obey,
you impudent fool?
You regret not telling your brother
not to go, right?
You still regret that he went to his death
without you saying anything!
So why are you trying
to do the same thing he did?
Why are you trying to make me suffer,
as your brother made you suffer?
Frederica...
Don't go, Shinei...
I don't want you to die like Kiri.
I don't want... I don't want
any more people to die.
I don't want to lose another big brother.
October 9th, Stellar Year 2149
I'm amazed Frederica agreed not to go.
I don't think she agreed.
She's locked up in her room
and not even coming to see us off.
She's the only one getting left behind.
That's enough reason to be grumpy.
If she's not going to the rear,
it doesn't matter what she is.
Everybody,
get on board!
Let's go.
Yeah.
Okay.
You're sleepy?
Normally I'd be asleep at this hour.
Sleep on the plane?
I can't sleep on planes.
Let's go.
Good luck.
I hope it doesn't need to get used.
Everybody strapped in?
30 minutes to mission start
Yes, ma'am.
You were telling the truth
about being the pilot, huh?
We don't have another choice.
Most of the old Air Force's pilots
died in combat.
I'm the only one who ever flew it
during the test flights.
You mentioned being
a former Air Force pilot.
You sound as though
you totally forgot until now, Lieutenant.
I'm sure you forgot this, too, then.
I'm opposed to kids like you
going out to fight.
To you Eighty-Six, fighting to the end here
is your source of pride, your identity.
But I'm not giving up on this, either.
If you're going to fight to the end,
then my job is to fight
alongside you as well.
The country you finally reached
is far from a utopia.
But remember this.
Not one person in this country
wants you to die in battle.
We want you to stay alive.
That goes for me, the Division Commander,
and the rest of the unit.
And me, too.
Hey, it's been a while.
How are you doing?
What are you doing?
I'm here to cheer you on, of course!
I'm the highest ranking officer
in the Federacy Army, after all.
The Federacy's people, its territory,
and its neighbors are all in danger.
I have to do at least this much.
Especially since you're the core
of this mission.
Yes.
Nordlicht's success in this mission will determine
the fate of the Federacy,
the surrounding countries, and humanity.
Keep that in mind.
And make sure you destroy the Morpho.
We know you can do it.
Roger.
And one more thing.
This is your highest-priority mission.
Come back alive.
All of you.
We'll do our best, but...
Right?
We can't promise.
That's not good enough.
You need to come back,
no matter what.
You're fighting to the end, right?
So you need to survive
till the end of the war.
So... come back.
No matter what.
That's right.
Come back, no matter what.
Or I'll...
destroy this world.
5 minutes to mission start
Mr. President.
Yes.
Let's get started.
Attention, comrades!
The Western Theater forces will begin
an all-out march into Legion-held territory.
This battle will determine not only the fate
of the Federal Republic of Giad,
but also those of the United Kingdom of
Roa Gracia, the Alliance of Wald,
and the other nations whose cries for help
we haven't even heard yet!
This is the greatest operation
in the history of mankind!
You are the mighty shield
that defends your homeland,
and the sharp sword
that cuts open a future for humanity!
We will be a symbol of justice
for the world!
Keep our successful battles
close to your heart
and advance, bravely, valiantly!
Begin the mission.
Fire!
Let's go, men!
Advance!
Flywheels 1 and 2 active.
Temporary transformer operating normally.
Initiating cooling of catapult rails.
Coolant units operating at 23% and rising.
Opening canopy. Deploying catapult rails.
All joint locks deployed.
Nachzehrer, ready for takeoff!
I've been waiting for this,
you pieces of scrap.
They're on the move!
Phase 1 complete.
We've succeeded in luring
the Legion vanguard out of position.
We will now move to phase 2.
Tiwaz HQ to Léraðr HQ.
Nachzehrer, you are cleared for take off!
Roger.
Okay, here we go!
Nachzehrer, take off!
Th-This is scarier than I thought.
Is the person who came up with this crazy?
Oh, it's an honor to have you say that!
I thought nothing scared you!
It's a little over 1000 km to our goal.
Enjoy our nine minutes or so
in the sky!
Nachzehrer has taken off successfully
and is proceeding as planned!
Unit 4, signal lost!
We've lost contact with the 2nd Company!
Stay calm! Unit 1, Unit 2, keep going forward!
Infantry, after us!
Retreat!
Damn it!
Give me a damage report! The battle's not over!
If you have something
you want to protect, then fight!
Raise your heads and go forward!
The Federacy isn't retreating.
Just a little more!
Just hang in there a little more!
And then those goddamn disgusting Eighty-Six will...
Then we'll win!
Yeah.
If we take out the Morpho, we win, right?
We have to live up to their expectations.
Yeah, if they're working that hard.
Yeah.
"If There's Something Worth Dying For."